Guide to the Rice University Dean of Natural Sciences records, 1963-1977 UA 020
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Dean of Natural Sciences records
1963-1977
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University.
UA 020
5.75 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
This collection contains correspondence, proposals, reports, budgets, and other materials related primarily to grants administered by the Dean of Natural Sciences (William E. Gordon) during the 1960s and 1970s.
5.75 linear ft. (12 boxes)
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence, proposals, reports, budgets, and other materials related primarily to grants administered by the Dean of Natural Sciences (William E. Gordon) during the 1960s and 1970s.
Access Restrictions
Boxes 11-12 (Guertin Lawsuit Records) are accessible only through permission of the President's Office of the Dean of Natural Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
official reports
- NASA-OWL Satellite Program, 1963-69; 150518
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1966-67; 150519 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1968-69; 150520 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Program proposals, 1963-68; 150521 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Progress reports #18-28, 150530 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Progress reports #29-42, 150531 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- NASA Training Grant, 1962-75; 150522
  - Status reports #1-3, 1962-63; 150523 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Status reports #4-5, 1963-64; 150524 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Status reports #6-7, 1964-65; 150525 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Status reports #8-9, 1965-66; 150526 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Status reports #10-11, 1966-67; 150527 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- NASA Training Grants Status Reports, 1963-75; 150528
  - Proposals and grants (NsG 9-62), 1962-75; 150529 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Status reports #1-11, 150545 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Status report #12, 1967-68; 150546 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Status report #13, 1968-69; 150547 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Status report #14, 1969-70; 150548 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Status report #15, 1970-71; 150549 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Status report #16, 1971-72; 150550 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- NIH Health Science Advancement Award, 1966-72; 150532
  - HSAA proposal, July 1966; 150533 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - HSAA proposal, February 1967; 150534 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - HSAA 1-SO4-FR-06136-01 grant and proposal, June 1968 - May 1969; 150535 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - HSAA general correspondence and information, 150536 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Notes in connection with HSAA Year IV budget, 150537 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - HSAA budget comparisons, 150538 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - HSAA policy statement, 150539 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Zerner Report (HSAA informal site visit), February 1970; 150540 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - HSAA site visit, Feburary 2-3, 1970; 150541 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Expenditure reports 404-022, 150542 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Biochemistry expenditure, HSAA sub-account 462-012, 150543 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - HSAA proposal, 1972-73; 150544 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - HSAA final progress report 5-SO4-RR-06136, 1974; 150551 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - HSAA 5-SO4-RR-06136-02 grant and proposal, June 1969 - May 1970; 150552 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - HSAA 5-SO4-RR-06136-03 grant and proposal, June 1970- May 1971; 150553 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - HSAA 5-SO4-RR-06136-04 grant and proposal, June 1971 - May 1972; 150554 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - THEMIS general correspondence, 150555 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - N00014-68-A-0503 proposals (Rabson), 150556 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - N00014-68-A-0503 correspondence (Rabson), 150557 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - N00014-68-A-0503 contract (Rabson), 150558 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - DACA39-69-C-0048 contract (Adams), 150559 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - DACA39-69-C-0048 correspondence (Adams), 150560 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - DACA39-69-C-0048 proposals (Adams), 150561 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
- NSF Systems Grant (Closed), 1967-70; 150562
  - Budget, 1967; 150563 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1969; 150564 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1970; 150565 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Expenditure items GU-1153, 150566 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Summer research GU-1153, 1969; 150567 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Speech Time Series Analysis Project: An English Spoken Digit Data Sampler, 1967; 150568 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- NSF Systems Grant, NSF Graduate Traineeship, 1964-71; 150569
  - Proposal, 1965; 150570 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - University Science Development Grant GU-1153, 150571 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Final report GU-1153, 1969; 150572 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Proposal, 1964; 150573 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Addendeum to extension proposal, 150574 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Proposal and notes, 1968; 150575 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Proposal for GU-1153 extension from March 1969 to February 1971, 150576 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Proposal on Systems Research and Engineering, 150577 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - GZ-2140, 102-093 Richter, 150578 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - GZ-1329, 02-073 Richter, 150579 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- THEMIS Project, 150580
  - HSAA coresspondence (sub-accounts), general, 150581 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - HSAA correspondence, Biology, 150582 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - HSAA correspondence, Chemical Engineering, 150583 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - HSAA correspondence, Chemistry, 150584 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - HSAA correspondence, Electrical Engineering, 150585 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - HSAA - Biology & Abercrombie Bldg. alteration and renovation, 150586 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - Summary Report on Development of Biochemistry Department for Terminal Report to National Institutes of Health for Health Science Advancement Award, 150587 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Guertin Lawsuit Records, 150588
  - Official correspondence, 150589 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Guertin and Schein depositions, 150590 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - GKW deposition and trial materials, 150591 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Guertin's teaching evaulation and reprints, 150592 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - G.K. Walters material for testimony, 150593 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)